<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<individual_metafile xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
    xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.cems.uwe.ac.uk/~p-chatterjee/2018-19/modules/dsa/assignment/individual_handin_schema.xsd">
    <!-- This file is an example of a valid individual metadata file. 
    Use this example file as a template and fill with your own data 
    validating as you go along using Oxygen or some other schema aware editor -->    
    <group id="F"/>
    <student id="17006647"/>
    <!--- List of one or more group components that you contributed to -->
    <component type="Photo Widget">
        <description>
          I Created a photo widget that drew photos from Flickr based on the woeid of the city being viewed
        </description>
        <problems>
          The actual widget pulling from Flickr and displaying the photos was very simple. I managed to do it in about 3 hours. But then when I started to look at caching,
          I started having the issue of too many data entries in localStorage (as I was storing 50 dataImageURLs for each city, as well as a timestamp (day and month) 
          for each photo. 
        </problems>
        <solutions>
          To counteract this, I made sure that only one date would be stored for each city in order to see whether or not to load the cached files or save
          new ones.
        </solutions>
        <problems>
          But even after doing this, sometimes it works flawlessly, but sometimes it will store all of one city perfectly, but if you try and go onto the second city
          only the first few will cache and the rest will not. I have spent probably close to 15 hours in total trying to get the caching to work, but this is the best I can do. 
        </problems>
        <hours_effort>18</hours_effort>
        <!-- This should be an URL to the working component - maybe part of the base page -->
        <base_url>http://www.cems.uwe.ac.uk/~an-other/dsa/assignment/index.php</base_url>
        <technologies>
            <tech>php</tech>
            <tech>javascript</tech>
            <tech>html5</tech>
            <tech>CSS</tech>
        </technologies>
        <source_files>
            <file>
                <name>flickr.php</name>
                <purpose>to fetch flickr photos</purpose>
                <source_url>http://www.cems.uwe.ac.uk/~an-other/php/dsa/flickr.phps</source_url>
            </file>
            <file>
                <name>index.html</name>
                <purpose>main page with embedded photos</purpose>
                <source_url>http://www.cems.uwe.ac.uk/~an-other/php/dsa/index.html</source_url>
            </file>
        </source_files>
    </component>
    <individual_comment>
      I really learnt a lot while doing this individual part. I learnt how to build up a URL that I could then call back to get JSON from in order to utilise the Flickr API.
      I also learnt a lot about caching and the difference between session storage and local storage. I also learnt about CSS as I had to style the images in a way that looked
      nice and didn't leave empty gaps everywhere where the image sizes were different.
    </individual_comment>
</individual_metafile>
<!-- DSA Individual Metadata File Example, 2018-19 -->
<!-- author: prakash.chatterjee@uwe.ac.uk -->
